<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Swim England North East</title>
	<atom:link href="https://asaner.org.uk/feed/?rand_id=1617751594" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://asaner.org.uk</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 12:12:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Increased Accessibility for North East Deaf Swimmers</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/increased-accessibility-for-north-east-deaf-swimmers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Small]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 12:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disability Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Swim England North East, Swim England and UK Deaf Sport are making huge grounds to ensure swimming is more accessible than ever before for deaf swimmers. The start of a race can be challenging for deaf athletes, especially those who are unable to wear their hearing aids or cochlear implants in the water. As part of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/increased-accessibility-for-north-east-deaf-swimmers/">Increased Accessibility for North East Deaf Swimmers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swim England North East, Swim England and UK Deaf Sport are making huge grounds to ensure swimming is more accessible than ever before for deaf swimmers.</p>
<p>The start of a race can be challenging for deaf athletes, especially those who are unable to wear their hearing aids or cochlear implants in the water. As part of an ongoing project, an unprecedented number of facilities in England which host level one and level two meets have been equipped with strobe lighting to ensure deaf swimmers have equal starts to their peers with the East Midlands area being the first to pilot these.</p>
<p>Swim England North East have been successful in securing funding from the Catherine Cookson Charitable Trust and the Rothley Trust which has enabled them to purchase three strobes that will be located within Northumberland and Durham and available for clubs to use.</p>
<p>As part of the partnership, UK Deaf Sport are offering to train volunteers to help them understand the unique information and support needs of deaf people. Deaf Awareness Training will be delivered in April’s online North East Swimming Coach Forum (1pm, 27th April 2021) enabling coaches to understand the barriers facing deaf people in swimming, help develop communication skills and be able to use them effectively in a coaching session and pathways for deaf swimming.</p>
<p>Swim England North East, Swim England and UK Deaf Sport are committed to making these changes nationwide, so deaf swimmers across the country have access to equal starts. They will  continue to seek to identify opportunities to support coaches, referees and officials through deaf awareness training and support.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/increased-accessibility-for-north-east-deaf-swimmers/">Increased Accessibility for North East Deaf Swimmers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>North East Region Youth Forum Share Their Lockdown Experiences</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-youth-forum-share-their-lockdown-experiences/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Parry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 07:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disability Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synchronised Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Polo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Swim England North East Region Youth Forum has put together a short video to capture, record and share their experience during lockdown. Representatives from each of the aquatic disciplines share their thoughts on various areas including: What they have missed while they have been out of the water What they have learned about themselves [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-youth-forum-share-their-lockdown-experiences/">North East Region Youth Forum Share Their Lockdown Experiences</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Swim England North East Region Youth Forum has put together a short video to capture, record and share their experience during lockdown. Representatives from each of the aquatic disciplines share their thoughts on various areas including:</p>
<ul>
<li>What they have missed while they have been out of the water</li>
<li>What they have learned about themselves</li>
<li>What they are looking forward to most when they return to the water</li>
<li>The concerns that they have about returning to pools</li>
<li>What has kept them engaged in their sport over the lockdown period</li>
</ul>
<p>The forum members organised the recording and produced it themselves.</p>
<p><iframe title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qw_I7q61I74" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>If young volunteers are interested in the forum please contact the Swim England North East Region at swimnortheast@swimming.org</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-youth-forum-share-their-lockdown-experiences/">North East Region Youth Forum Share Their Lockdown Experiences</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>COVID-19 Financial Support Guide for Clubs</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/covid-19-financial-support-guide-for-clubs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Small]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 13:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Water Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synchronised Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Polo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24799</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Swim England have recently produced a Financial Support Guide for clubs. It can be downloaded via the following link: COVID-19 Financial Support Guide for Clubs. Please can you share this with anyone who may find it useful.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/covid-19-financial-support-guide-for-clubs/">COVID-19 Financial Support Guide for Clubs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swim England have recently produced a Financial Support Guide for clubs. It can be downloaded via the following link: <a href="https://asaner.org.uk/mdocs-posts/covid-19-financial-support-guide-for-clubs/">COVID-19 Financial Support Guide for Clubs.</a></p>
<p>Please can you share this with anyone who may find it useful.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/covid-19-financial-support-guide-for-clubs/">COVID-19 Financial Support Guide for Clubs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swim England Water Polo Workshops</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-water-polo-nutritional-workshops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Tjaguns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 11:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Polo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>7 Nutritional Workshops now online for all water polo players. First one starts tomorrow 6.30pm 1st April. Not exclusive to water polo &#8211; all athletes would benefit from attending these presentations. Access to the workshops via Swim England Shop https://shop.swimming.org/water-polo-webinars</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-water-polo-nutritional-workshops/">Swim England Water Polo Workshops</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>7 Nutritional Workshops now online for all water polo players.</p>
<p>First one starts tomorrow 6.30pm 1<sup>st</sup> April.</p>
<p>Not exclusive to water polo &#8211; all athletes would benefit from attending these presentations.</p>
<p>Access to the workshops via Swim England Shop</p>
<p><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/DkdHCwK4xHxMO8iqFSem?domain=shop.swimming.org">https://shop.swimming.org/water-polo-webinars</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-water-polo-nutritional-workshops/">Swim England Water Polo Workshops</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Outdoor Swimming Webinar Series</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/outdoor-swimming-webinar-series/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Parry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Water Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Swim England are offering FREE Outdoor Swimming Webinar series, supported by Outdoor Swimmer Magazine. The launch of the series was so popular that we sold out in just one day! However, due to the high demand,  additional places are available on all three sessions. There are two topics on offer. The Introduction to Outdoor Swimming [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/outdoor-swimming-webinar-series/">Outdoor Swimming Webinar Series</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swim England are offering FREE Outdoor Swimming Webinar series, supported by <strong>Outdoor Swimmer Magazine</strong>.</p>
<p>The launch of the series was so popular that we sold out in just one day! However, due to the high demand,  additional places are available on all three sessions.</p>
<p>There are two topics on offer. The <em>Introduction to Outdoor Swimming </em>will run twice &#8211; please <strong>don&#8217;t</strong> book onto both sessions.</p>
<p><strong>• Introduction to Outdoor Swimming, Tuesday 6 April, 8pm-9pm<br />
• Introduction to Outdoor Swimming, Wednesday 7 April, 1pm-2pm<br />
• Outdoor Swimming Q and A with expert panel, Thursday 8 April, 7.30pm-8.30pm</strong></p>
<p>Places can be booked at: <a href="https://asa.formstack.com/forms/outdoor_swimming_webinars">https://asa.formstack.com/forms/outdoor_swimming_webinars</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/outdoor-swimming-webinar-series/">Outdoor Swimming Webinar Series</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New training opportunity launched in national diving judge course</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/new-training-opportunity-launched-in-national-diving-judge-course/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Tjaguns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 10:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Officials]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24730</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Swim England is excited to launch a new training opportunity for volunteers and members which will see them progressing in their journey of becoming a diving judge. This course is aimed at any Swim England members who wish to gain an initial understanding of Diving FINA Rules and apply this within their club and regional [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/new-training-opportunity-launched-in-national-diving-judge-course/">New training opportunity launched in national diving judge course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swim England is excited to launch a new training opportunity for volunteers and members which will see them progressing in their journey of becoming a diving judge.</p>
<p>This course is aimed at any Swim England members who wish to gain an initial understanding of Diving FINA Rules and apply this within their club and regional events organised by the region.</p>
<p>The course will be held virtually on Tuesday 6 April at 6.30 pm. It will enable participants to develop their knowledge of judging in diving and build on the basics they will have learned from completing the <a title="" href="https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/DivingJudging" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Introduction to Diving Judging resource</a> which participants are encouraged to complete prior to attending.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.swimming.org/diving/national-diving-j1-course/">Click here for further details.</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/new-training-opportunity-launched-in-national-diving-judge-course/">New training opportunity launched in national diving judge course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>North East Diving Nutrition Workshop &#8211; 10/4/21</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-diving-nutrition-workshop-10-4-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Tjaguns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Time: 11.30-12.30pm Cost: £3.00 Number Restrictions: 100 Divers must be Category 1 or 2 Youth Sport Nutrition will be holding a virtual workshop on the fundamentals of nutrition for youth athletes in diving. The workshop will be taken by Emmy Campbell, Lead Nutritionist for Youth Sport Nutrition. This interactive session will cover all of the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-diving-nutrition-workshop-10-4-21/">North East Diving Nutrition Workshop &#8211; 10/4/21</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time: 11.30-12.30pm<br />
Cost: £3.00<br />
Number Restrictions: 100<br />
Divers must be Category 1 or 2</p>
<p>Youth Sport Nutrition will be holding a virtual workshop on the fundamentals of nutrition for youth athletes in diving. The workshop will be taken by Emmy Campbell, Lead Nutritionist for Youth Sport Nutrition. This interactive session will cover all of the basics of nutrition for good health, as well as covering exactly what to eat and when to get the most out of your training days and take your diving to the next level. Younger athletes should be accompanied on this workshop by a parent/carer. Everyone who attends will receive a link after the workshop to book an optional free 15 minute individual diver and parent/carer consultation with Emmy.</p>
<p><a href="https://asaner.org.uk/event/nutrition-foundation-workshop-for-divers/">Click here to book on</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-diving-nutrition-workshop-10-4-21/">North East Diving Nutrition Workshop &#8211; 10/4/21</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regional Swimming Championships (50m) 2021 &#8211; Update</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/regional-swimming-championships-50m-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Tjaguns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Swimmers and Parents/Carers will realise that it would not be possible to deliver the Regional Swimming Championships in April/May 2021 with the current social distancing rules are in place. The indications are that the current social distancing restrictions will not be relaxed by HM Government for some time. Although age group swimmers could be allowed [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/regional-swimming-championships-50m-2021/">Regional Swimming Championships (50m) 2021 &#8211; Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swimmers and Parents/Carers will realise that it would not be possible to deliver the Regional Swimming Championships in April/May 2021 with the current social distancing rules are in place.</p>
<p>The indications are that the current social distancing restrictions will not be relaxed by HM Government for some time.<br />
Although age group swimmers could be allowed to return to the pool on 12th April (not confirmed until 5th April) senior swimmers will not be returning until after the Championships would have taken place.</p>
<p>Clearly most age group swimmers would not be fit enough to compete in a Regional Championships two weeks after returning to the pool.</p>
<p>The Swim England Swimming Leadership Group are working on plans to enable competitive swimming to return as soon as conditions allow. We will keep you updated on progress.</p>
<p>We hope that it may be possible to hold our Regional Championships (25m) in November 2021 as planned.<br />
I realise that this will be a disappointment to many swimmers but the safety of our members must take priority over all other considerations.</p>
<p>Barry J Saunders, Swimming Manager, Swim England North East Region</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/regional-swimming-championships-50m-2021/">Regional Swimming Championships (50m) 2021 &#8211; Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Free Swim England Club Chair and Welfare Officer Workshops Spring 2021</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/free-swim-england-club-chair-and-welfare-officer-workshops-spring-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Small]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 20:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Water Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synchronised Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Polo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the next few months, Swim England will be delivering a delivering a number of workshops and information sessions to Club Welfare Officers and Club Chairs. The Welfare Officer workshop is designed to give people in the role more support and understanding of expectations around their role. It does not replace the need for Time [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/free-swim-england-club-chair-and-welfare-officer-workshops-spring-2021/">Free Swim England Club Chair and Welfare Officer Workshops Spring 2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the next few months, Swim England will be delivering a delivering a number of workshops and information sessions to Club Welfare Officers and Club Chairs.</p>
<p>The Welfare Officer workshop is designed to give people in the role more support and understanding of expectations around their role. It does not replace the need for Time to Listen or Safeguarding. This Chairs information session is specifically designed to cover dealing with internal club disputes, using the constitution and understanding the role the Chair plays in supporting the overall governance of the club. Each workshop or session is limited to 30 places and will be delivered online via Zoom.</p>
<p>Dates for both the Chair and Welfare Officers sessions can be found in the links below:</p>
<ul>
<li>Club Chair: <a href="https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/ClubChairSessions">https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/ClubChairSessions</a>.</li>
<li>Club Welfare: <a href="https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/Welfareofficerworkshops">https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/Welfareofficerworkshops</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Please can you share this information with anyone who might be interested in attending.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/free-swim-england-club-chair-and-welfare-officer-workshops-spring-2021/">Free Swim England Club Chair and Welfare Officer Workshops Spring 2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swim England Covid-19 Guidance Forums</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-covid-19-guidance-forums/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Small]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 20:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Officials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Water Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Polo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=24681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Prior to pools reopening in April, Swim England are running a number of national Covid-19 Guidance forums. Sessions are open to all Covid-19 leads and club officers and can be booked onto via the following link: https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/ClubGuidanceUpdates.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-covid-19-guidance-forums/">Swim England Covid-19 Guidance Forums</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prior to pools reopening in April, Swim England are running a number of national Covid-19 Guidance forums. Sessions are open to all Covid-19 leads and club officers and can be booked onto via the following link: <a href="https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/ClubGuidanceUpdates">https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/ClubGuidanceUpdates</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-covid-19-guidance-forums/">Swim England Covid-19 Guidance Forums</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
